followupthen.com 2019-09-16

# Privacy Policy | FollowUpThen

#### Our Policy

Welcome to the website (the " **Site** ") of FollowUpThen, Inc. (" **FollowUpThen** ", "we", "us" and/or "our"). This Site is operated by FollowUpThen and has been created to provide information about our company and its reminder services (together with the Site, the " **Services** ") to our Service visitors ("you", "your"). This Privacy Policy sets forth FollowUpThen’s policy with respect to information including personally identifiable data (" **Personal Data** ") and other information that is collected from visitors to the Site and Services. 

#### A Note About Email Content:

Our Service allows users to forward emails to our Service for the purpose of setting automated reminders associated with those emails. We recognize that your emails may be very private, and we take special care with them. For example, we encrypt the message body of these emails using industry-standard methodologies for long-term storage on our servers. We store the content of these emails for the period of time required in order to send you the requested reminder. After the requested reminder period has expired and the Service has sent the reminder, we delete the message body, message text and attachments after a "reminder retention period", when the user can choose to postpone the reminder until a later date. The retention period is variable based on the account level, ranging between 2 weeks (for free accounts) and 6 months for "Company" accounts. For example, if you are on the free plan and forward an email to 5months@followupthen.com, we retain the complete email information for five (5) months plus six (2) weeks. Postponing the followup will extend the length of time the data persists in our system. 

In the rare event that the content of an email interferes with the operation of the Service (ie, due to a bug), the problematic email may be temporarily logged in full or otherwise viewed for the purposes of debugging. With respect to other email-related information, we store the subject heading of these emails unencrypted for the sole purpose of performing internal quality assurance and de-bugging. We also retain certain non-personally identifiable information related to these emails (for example, date sent, email configuration, name of the email provider), for the purpose of improving our Services and as described below in the "Non-Identifiable Data" section. 

#### Information We Collect:

When you interact with us through the Services, we may collect Personal Data and other information from you, as further described below: 

  * **Personal Data That You Provide Through the Services:**

We collect Personal Data including name, email address telephone number, mailing address phone number, credit card number, username and password when you voluntarily provide such information, such as when you contact us with inquiries, respond to one of our surveys, register for access to the FollowUpThen Services or use certain FollowUpThen Services. Our customer relationship tools (ie, Intercom.io) make use of your IP address and email address to automatically discover your social media profiles and approximate location. We use this data to provide better, more personalized support or to contact you with relevant information about FollowUpThen. Where FollowUpThen collects voluntary Personal Data we make an effort to provide a link to this Privacy Policy. 

  * **Personal Data of Non-Users:**

The Service may allow users to enable reminders for the people with whom they communicate. As part of this service, we will collect the email address(es) provided by our users in order to provide this feature. We use the email addresses of non-users only in connection with providing the requested feature (for example, to send the reminder as requested by one of our users). If you are not a user of our Service and do not wish to receive a reminder from the Services, please click the opt out link in the reminder email that you receive. If you do opt-out, we will keep your email address on file for the sole purpose of ensuring we never contact you without your permission. If you do not opt out from the reminder, then we will delete your email address and the applicable email within the time period described above in the Section called “A Note About Email Content.” 

**By voluntarily providing us with Personal Data, you are consenting to our use of it in accordance with this Privacy Policy. If you provide Personal Data to the Services, you acknowledge and agree that such Personal Data may be transferred from your current location to the offices and servers of FollowUpThen and the authorized third parties referred to herein located in the United States.**

#### Other Information:

  * **Non-Identifiable Data:**

When you interact with FollowUpThen through the Services, we receive and store certain personally non-identifiable information. Such information, which is collected passively using various technologies, cannot presently be used to specifically identify you. FollowUpThen may store such information itself or such information may be included in databases owned and maintained by FollowUpThen affiliates, agents or service providers. The Services may use such information and pool it with other information to track, for example, the total number of visitors to our Site, the languages of users, time zones, location, name of the email client, the configuration of the email client, and the domain names of our visitors' Internet service providers. It is important to note that no Personal Data is available or used in this process.   
In operating the Services, we may use a technology called "cookies." A cookie is a piece of information that the computer that hosts our Services gives to your browser when you access the Services. Our cookies help provide additional functionality to the Services and help us analyze Services usage more accurately. For instance, the Site may set a cookie on your browser that allows you to access the Site without needing to remember and then enter a password more than once during a visit to the Services. In all cases in which we use cookies, we will not collect Personal Data except with your permission. On most web browsers, you will find a “help” section on the toolbar. Please refer to this section for information on how to receive notification when you are receiving a new cookie and how to turn cookies off. We recommend that you leave cookies turned on because they allow you to take advantage of some of the Services’ features. 

  * **Location Information:**

Our Service may collect and use your location information to provide certain functionality of our Service (for example, associating a reminder with a particular location). We may also use your location information in an aggregate way, as described below in the “Aggregated Personal Data” section. 

  * **Aggregated Personal Data:**

In an ongoing effort to better understand and serve the users of the FollowUpThen Services, FollowUpThen often conducts research on its user demographics, interests and behavior based on the Personal Data and other information provided to us. This research may be compiled and analyzed on an aggregate basis, and FollowUpThen may share this aggregate data with its affiliates, agents and business partners. This aggregate information does not identify you personally. FollowUpThen may also disclose aggregated user statistics in order to describe our services to current and prospective business partners, and to other third parties for other lawful purposes. 

#### Our Use of Your Personal Data and Other Information:

FollowUpThen uses the Personal Data you provide in a manner that is consistent with this Privacy Policy. If you provide Personal Data for a certain reason, we may use the Personal Data in connection with the reason for which it was provided. For instance, if you contact us by e-mail, we will use the Personal Data you provide to send you a reminder, answer your question or resolve your problem. Also, if you provide Personal Data in order to obtain access to (for example, by accessing your account settings) or use (for example, by setting or modifying reminders) the FollowUpThen Services, we will use your Personal Data to provide you with access to such services and to monitor your use of such services. FollowUpThen and its subsidiaries and affiliates (the “FollowUpThen Related Companies”) may also use your Personal Data and other personally non-identifiable information collected through the Services to help us improve the content and functionality of the Services, to better understand our users and to improve the FollowUpThen Services. FollowUpThen and its affiliates may use this information to contact you in the future to tell you about services we believe will be of interest to you, as well as communications (such as newsletters) about FollowUpThen and the Service. If we do so, each marketing communication we send you will contain instructions permitting you to "opt-out" of receiving future marketing communications. In addition, if at any time you wish not to receive any future marketing communications or you wish to have your name deleted from our mailing lists, please contact us as indicated below.   
As previously mentioned, email content is encrypted in our database, however, in the course of providing system administration, debugging and support, it may be necessary for a FollowUpThen staff member to view unencrypted content or login under a user's account to provide this support. Such interactions are limited to only technical support and system administration instances.   
If your Personal Data is provided by others using the Service, your Personal Data is used only in connection with the Services (for example, to provide you with the reminders others schedule for you).   
If FollowUpThen intends on using any Personal Data in any manner that is not consistent with this Privacy Policy, you will be informed of such anticipated use prior to or at the time at which the Personal Data is collected. 

#### Deleting Your Account

FollowUpThen provides a link for you to delete your account. This action permanently removes your data from our database including your tasks, account information and data stored with 3rd party vendors, for example our credit card processor. Your account will remain in archival database backups, used only for disaster recovery scenarios, until the backup has been purged as a natural part of our backup retention policy. Logs, which contain ip addresses and email headers (including to, cc, bcc and subject fields) are purged 4 weeks after deleting your account. 

#### Export Your Data

FollowUpThen a link in your account settings to export your followups as portable, open CSV file. We respect your right to choose the best tool for email reminders.

#### Our Disclosure of Your Personal Data and Other Information:

FollowUpThen is not in the business of selling your information. We consider this information to be a vital part of our relationship with you. There are, however, certain circumstances in which we may share your Personal Data with certain third parties without further notice to you, as set forth below: 

  * **Business Transfers:**

As we develop our business, we might sell or buy businesses or assets. In the event of a corporate sale, merger, reorganization, dissolution or similar event, Personal Data may be part of the transferred assets. One important factor in any such transaction would be the degree to which the receiving party shares similar values regarding the treatment of your Personal Data. 

  * **FollowUpThen Related Companies:**

We may also share your Personal Data with the FollowUpThen Related Companies for purposes consistent with this Privacy Policy. 

  * **Agents, Consultants and Related Third Parties:**

FollowUpThen, like many businesses, sometimes hires other companies to perform certain business-related functions. Examples of such functions include mailing information, maintaining databases and processing payments. When we employ another company to perform a function of this nature, we only provide them with the information that they need to perform their specific function. FollowUpThen, employees and contractors that are required to have full access to the system (ie, DevOps) are carefully interviewed and vetted over a period of time before they are permitted access.

  * **Legal Requirements:**

FollowUpThen may disclose your Personal Data if required to do so by law or in the good faith belief that such action is necessary to (i) comply with a legal obligation, (ii) protect and defend the rights or property of FollowUpThen, (iii) act in urgent circumstances to protect the personal safety of users of the Services or the public, or (iv) protect against legal liability. 

#### Company and Employee Accounts:

All information submitted to FollowUpThen as an employee account is owned by the company account administrator who has permission to view, change or delete information within in the account. 

#### Company and Employee Accounts:

All information submitted to FollowUpThen as an employee account is owned by the company account administrator who has permission to view, change or delete information within the account. 

#### Your Choices:

You can visit the Services without providing any Personal Data. If you choose not to provide any Personal Data, you may not be able to use certain FollowUpThen Services. 

#### SMS Messages:

The Service may allow you to send SMS (text message) reminders to your own mobile device using the Service. Please report any SMS or other abuse related to the Service to help@humans.fut.io. To get help, email us at help@humans.fut.io or call (408) 246-9500. 

#### Exclusions:

This Privacy Policy does not apply to any Personal Data collected by FollowUpThen other than Personal Data collected through the Services. This Privacy Policy shall not apply to any unsolicited information you provide to FollowUpThen through the Services or through any other means. This includes, but is not limited to, information posted to any public areas of the Services, such as forums (collectively, “Public Areas”), any ideas for new products or modifications to existing products, and other unsolicited submissions (collectively, “Unsolicited Information”). All Unsolicited Information shall be deemed to be non-confidential and FollowUpThen shall be free to reproduce, use, disclose, and distribute such Unsolicited Information to others without limitation or attribution. 

#### Children:

FollowUpThen does not knowingly collect Personal Data from children under the age of 13. If you are under the age of 13, please do not submit any Personal Data through the Services. We encourage parents and legal guardians to monitor their children’s Internet usage and to help enforce our Privacy Policy by instructing their children never to provide Personal Data on the Services without their permission. If you have reason to believe that a child under the age of 13 has provided Personal Data to FollowUpThen through the Services, please contact us, and we will endeavor to delete that information from our databases. 

#### Connected Services:

FollowUpThen provides optional connections to 3rd party services via the "Connected Services" settings page. By signing up for a connected service, or authorizing it to act on your personal information, you are creating a separate agreement with that company and should take the time to understand their privacy policy. The action of using the connected service is treated as an acceptance of the terms of their terms of use and privacy policy. 

**Google** FollowUpThen provides an option for you to connect your Google account to enable additional productivity features such as response detection. We request only the permissions necessary to perform these productivity features. For example, response detetion only requires access to message-ids to determine if an email is a reply to an earlier email. We therefore only request visibility into email headers for your Gmail account, not your email message content. We securely store ids, timestamps and access tokens which permit this limited access to your inbox and do not share this information 3rd parties or use it for marketing, market research, email campaign tracking or purposes other than those described in the FollowUpThen feature list. To further ensure the security of your data, this information is stored and used in a stand-alone microservice which itself contains numerous restrictions and security layers. If you choose to delete your FollowUpThen account, this connection to your Google inbox and all information stored from your Google account is also permanently deleted. 

**Context.IO** FollowUpThen provides certain user accounts with the option to connect their email inboxes to Context.IO in order to provide additional productivity features in FollowUpThen. By connecting your email inbox to ContextIO, you are agreeing to their [privacy policy](https://returnpath.com/data-privacy-policy/) which includes sharing Personal Information with those who provide the Context.IO service: DokDok, Inc. and its parent company, Return Path, Inc. and their affiliates (collectively “Context.IO Providers”). Context.IO Providers may access and use your Personal Information to carry out work on our behalf (such as monitoring your inbox for a reply to a specific message so that it can be canceled). FollowUpThen subscribes to the paid Context.io plans, thereby opting out our users from sharing anonymous data with Return Path, Inc. To interact with Context.io and your email inbox, FollowUpThen stores a token that permits access to all messages in your email inbox. This token is used only, however, to detect the arrival of email messages and their corresponding message-ids. 

#### Links to Other Web Sites: 

This Privacy Policy applies only to the Services. The Services may contain links to other web sites not operated or controlled by FollowUpThen (the “Third Party Sites”). The policies and procedures we described here do not apply to the Third Party Sites. The links from the Services do not imply that FollowUpThen endorses or has reviewed the Third Party Sites. We suggest contacting those sites directly for information on their privacy policies. 

#### Security:

FollowUpThen takes reasonable steps to protect the Personal Data provided via the Services from loss, misuse, and unauthorized access, disclosure, alteration, or destruction. However, no Internet or e-mail transmission is ever fully secure or error free. In particular, e-mail sent to or from the Services may not be secure. Therefore, you should take special care in deciding what information you send to us via e-mail. Please keep this in mind when disclosing any Personal Data to FollowUpThen via the Internet. 

#### Other Terms and Conditions:

Your access to and use of the Services is subject to the Terms of Use at http://www.followupthen.com/terms. 

#### Changes to FollowUpThen’s Privacy Policy:

The Services and our business may change from time to time. As a result, at times it may be necessary for FollowUpThen to make changes to this Privacy Policy. FollowUpThen reserves the right to update or modify this Privacy Policy at any time and from time to time without prior notice. Please review this policy periodically, and especially before you provide any Personal Data. This Privacy Policy was last updated on the date indicated above. Your continued use of the Services after any changes or revisions to this Privacy Policy shall indicate your agreement with the terms of such revised Privacy Policy. 

#### Access to Information; Contacting FollowUpThen:

To keep your Personal Data accurate, current, and complete, please contact us as specified below. We will take reasonable steps to update or correct Personal Data in our possession that you have previously submitted via the Services.   
Please also feel free to contact us if you have any questions about FollowUpThen’s Privacy Policy or the information practices of the Services. 

You may contact us as follows:  
FollowUpThen, Inc  
1101 South Winchester Ave, St E-157  
San Jose, CA 95128  
help@humans.fut.io
